<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Join Diaspora Blog</title>
 <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-09-14T12:57:42-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>diaspora</name>
   <email>team@joindiaspora.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>How We Connect Users</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/09/14/user-discovery-between-pods.html"/>
   <updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/09/14/user-discovery-between-pods</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;How We Connect Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;14 September 2011&lt;br /&gt;
by Sarah Mei&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this is the first in a series of technical posts about Diaspora&amp;#8217;s software architecture and code. If you have topics you&amp;#8217;d like to see covered in future installments, please let us know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single installation of the Diaspora software is called a &lt;strong&gt;pod&lt;/strong&gt;. The Diaspora distributed network is made up of hundreds of these pods, each with a set of users &amp;#8211; sometimes just one on an individual pod, sometimes tens of thousands on a community pod. Each pod is run by a different person or organization. But no matter what pod you sign up on, you can connect with users on any other pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have friends on different pods, your stream seamlessly mixes updates from remote friends with updates from friends on your pod. In this way Diaspora is a &lt;strong&gt;distributed&lt;/strong&gt; social network that resembles, from the user&amp;#8217;s perspective, a &lt;strong&gt;centralized&lt;/strong&gt; social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sept2011/diaspora_screenshot.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Users from different pods interact seamlessly in posts and comments in the main stream&quot; alt=&quot;Users from different pods interact seamlessly in posts and comments in the main stream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do these users find each other? In a centralized system, all servers access the same database, so when you search for a friend, there&amp;#8217;s only one place to look. But in the Diaspora ecosystem, each pod has its own database, inaccessible to the other pods. So how does pod A figure out who&amp;#8217;s on pod B, or for that matter, pod C that&amp;#8217;s never been heard from before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all starts with searching. Let&amp;#8217;s say you&amp;#8217;re setting up your own pod. Once you&amp;#8217;ve downloaded the Diaspora source and gotten it running on a server accessible to the internet, you open it up, log in&amp;#8230;and are faced with the vast emptiness of splendid isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s get you some friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no central server that keeps a list of existing pods or existing users. Instead, Diaspora depends on an emerging-standard protocol called &lt;a href=&quot;http://hueniverse.com/webfinger&quot;&gt;webfinger&lt;/a&gt; to discover users on remote pods. This all kicks off when you search for someone&amp;#8217;s &lt;b&gt;Diaspora ID&lt;/b&gt; in your pod&amp;#8217;s search box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aside:&lt;/b&gt; A Diaspora ID is made up of a username, followed by an @ sign, followed by the pod url. It looks a lot like an email address. But just like with Jabber IDs which also look like email addresses, you can&amp;#8217;t send email to it. It&amp;#8217;s just a unique identifier within the Diaspora ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;#8217;ve talked to a friend who&amp;#8217;s on a (fictional) pod called otherpod.com, and you&amp;#8217;ve gotten her Diaspora ID &amp;#8211; sarah@otherpod.com. You want to connect, so you put sarah@otherpod.com into the search box on your pod and hit go. A few seconds later, you see her information on the search page with a nice &amp;#8220;Add to Aspect&amp;#8221; button alongside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to claim that, but sadly ponycorns are in short supply around here. Here&amp;#8217;s how it goes down behind the scenes. A detailed explanation follows the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sept2011/user_discovery.jpg&quot; title=&quot;User discovery flowchart&quot; alt=&quot;User discovery flowchart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it gets a search request for a Diaspora ID, the first thing your pod does is look in its local database to see if it already knows about this person. This is the grey diamond in the diagram. If it can skip all this drama and just show you the information, it does so. But because you&amp;#8217;re on a brand new pod, the only user it knows about is you. So it prepares to retrieve the information you requested from the remote pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here the process is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt; Figure out where to search&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt; Search&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt; Retrieve detailed information&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;4.&lt;/b&gt; Cache data locally&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;5.&lt;/b&gt; Profit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose the last one is optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Find out where to search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your pod extracts the pod &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; from the Diaspora ID (sarah@otherpod.com becomes otherpod.com) and appends a standard location called &amp;#8220;the host-meta route&amp;#8221; to get this &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;http://otherpod.com/.well-known/host-meta&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This route is part of the webfinger standard. It&amp;#8217;s the basic way you ask a server whether or not it supports webfinger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your pod then accesses this location and gets back a piece of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; in a format called &lt;a href=&quot;http://hueniverse.com/xrd/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, accessing the host-meta route is the same as asking the pod, &amp;#8220;How should I send you inquiries about users?&amp;#8221; The &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt; document that it returns tells your pod how to construct the query for the particular user you&amp;#8217;re interested in. Here&amp;#8217;s what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
1 &amp;lt;?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?&amp;gt;
2 &amp;lt;XRD xmlns='http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/xri/xrd-1.0' xmlns:hm='http://host-meta.net/xrd/1.0'&amp;gt;
3   &amp;lt;hm:Host&amp;gt;otherpod.com&amp;lt;/hm:Host&amp;gt;
4   &amp;lt;Link rel='lrdd' template='https://otherpod.com/webfinger?q={uri}'&amp;gt;
5     &amp;lt;Title&amp;gt;Resource Descriptor&amp;lt;/Title&amp;gt;
6   &amp;lt;/Link&amp;gt;
7 &amp;lt;/XRD&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;template&amp;#8221; on line 4 is the key. It tells your pod to query for the user by substituting their Diaspora ID for {uri}. So to search for your friend, your pod needs to construct need a &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;https://otherpod.com/webfinger?q=sarah@otherpod.com&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aside:&lt;/b&gt; All Diaspora pods accept user queries at the same location, so this step might seem redundant. But Diaspora pods also inter-operate with other, non-Diaspora social systems, and those may have different locations for querying for a user. In other words, when we get a Diaspora ID, we don&amp;#8217;t actually know whether the pod is a Diaspora pod or something else. So we ask for the search route each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having figured out the right way to ask, your pod now queries for the user it wants. It accesses the query &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;https://otherpod.com/webfinger?q=sarah@otherpod.com&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This returns us another piece of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8211; another &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt; document &amp;#8211; that gives us some basic information about the user, but mostly just tells us where to go to find more detailed info. Here&amp;#8217;s what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
 1 &amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;
 2 &amp;lt;XRD xmlns=&quot;http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/xri/xrd-1.0&quot;&amp;gt;
 3   &amp;lt;Subject&amp;gt;acct:sarah@otherpod.com&amp;lt;/Subject&amp;gt;
 4   &amp;lt;Alias&amp;gt;&quot;https://otherpod.com/&quot;&amp;lt;/Alias&amp;gt;
 5   &amp;lt;Link rel=&quot;http://microformats.org/profile/hcard&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; href=&quot;https://otherpod.com/hcard/users/4cec1e372c174347b90000ad&quot;/&amp;gt;
 6   &amp;lt;Link rel=&quot;http://otherpod.com/seed_location&quot; type = 'text/html' href=&quot;https://otherpod.com/&quot;/&amp;gt;
 7   &amp;lt;Link rel=&quot;http://otherpod.com/guid&quot; type = 'text/html' href=&quot;4cec1e372c174347b90000ad&quot;/&amp;gt;
 8   &amp;lt;Link rel='http://webfinger.net/rel/profile-page' type='text/html' href='https://otherpod.com/u/sarah'/&amp;gt;
 9   &amp;lt;Link rel=&quot;http://schemas.google.com/g/2010#updates-from&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot; href=&quot;https://otherpod.com/public/sarah.atom&quot;/&amp;gt;
10   &amp;lt;Link rel=&quot;diaspora-public-key&quot; type = 'RSA' href=&quot;[public key omitted for length]&quot;/&amp;gt;
11 &amp;lt;/XRD&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aside:&lt;/b&gt; The webfinger &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt; document is supposed to be just links to information elsewhere. However, as you can see, Diaspora embeds some actual information, such as the person&amp;#8217;s public key, in the document. We implemented this before we fully understood how &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt; was supposed to work. We should at some point move that information to the hcard (see next section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Retrieve profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fill out profile details, the pod extracts the &amp;#8220;hcard location&amp;#8221; from the webfinger &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XRD&lt;/span&gt; document. An hcard is a standard, structured way to represent profile data in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;. The hcard location is on line 5 of the document above, with &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;https://otherpod.com/hcard/users/4cec1e372c174347b90000ad&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your pod accesses the hcard location, and gets back a piece of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; with additional profile details for the remote user, such as name. Here&amp;#8217;s an excerpt of that hcard &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s quite long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
 1 &amp;lt;div id='content'&amp;gt;
 2   &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Sarah Mei&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
 3   &amp;lt;div id='content_inner'&amp;gt;
 4     &amp;lt;div class='entity_profile vcard author' id='i'&amp;gt;
 5       &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;User profile&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
 6       &amp;lt;dl class='entity_nickname'&amp;gt;
 7         &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt;Nickname&amp;lt;/dt&amp;gt;
 8         &amp;lt;dd&amp;gt;
 9           &amp;lt;a class='nickname url uid' href='https://otherpod.com/' rel='me'&amp;gt;Sarah Mei&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
10         &amp;lt;/dd&amp;gt;
11       &amp;lt;/dl&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes on, but I think you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Cache data locally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, having searched for the user and then retrieved her hcard, your pod extracts the profile details and saves them in its local database. sarah@otherpod.com now shows up in searches you do on your pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Profit!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you start following your friend, you&amp;#8217;ll get her updates as though she were a user local to your pod. If she also follows you, she&amp;#8217;ll get your updates in her stream too. From there&amp;#8230;who knows what could happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This walkthrough covered just searching and basic user discovery, which is a tiny part of how Diaspora pods interoperate. Once you get into federation of posts and other content between pods, it&amp;#8217;s a whole different ballgame. Stay tuned for that in an upcoming installment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Diaspora* is making a difference</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/09/08/we-are-making-a-difference.html"/>
   <updated>2011-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/09/08/we-are-making-a-difference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Diaspora* is making a difference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;08 September 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we’ve been quiet for a while, it’s because we’ve been working hard, head-down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re thrilled to say we’ve built the first stage of a new social web, one better than what’s out there today: a place where each of us owns our own information, where each person controls his or her own privacy, where no-one is a product, and where we all control our own destinies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re sending out alpha invitations to everyone now, as quickly as we can.  If you’re waiting and haven’t gotten yours yet, you will receive it by the end of October.  Or, &lt;a href=&quot;https://joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt; if you haven’t already.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s been big news in the social networking world recently, and &lt;strong&gt;we can’t help but be pleased with the impact our work has had on two of the biggest developments.&lt;/strong&gt;  We’re proud that Google+ imitated one of our core features, aspects, with their circles.  And now Facebook is at last moving in the right direction with user control over privacy, a move spurred not just by Google+, but more fundamentally by you and tens of thousands of community members, as well as hundreds of thousands of people who’ve lined up to try Diaspora* &amp;#8212; that is, by all of us who’ve stood up to say “there has to be a better way.”  We’re making a difference already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And &lt;em&gt;aspects&lt;/em&gt; is just one of the many ways we’re pioneering the future of the social web.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick preview of some of the other ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We’ll make the social web more fun than it is today.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Our distributed design gives you the security of owning your own identity and data.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This also gives you the freedom to do what you want online.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Our ecosystem provides the commons, the connective tissue for an evolving social web.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We’re not gatekeepers, so our ecosystem will always support the latest apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll tell you a little more about each of these points in the weeks ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, thanks again for your interest and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maxwell, Daniel, Ilya, Sarah, Yosem and Peter&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Diaspora Project -  First Year In Graphs</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/06/01/graphs-graphs-graphs.html"/>
   <updated>2011-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/06/01/graphs-graphs-graphs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Diaspora Project &amp;#8211;  First Year In Graphs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 June 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/june01/beaver.png&quot; title=&quot;a card my sister got me for my birthday&quot; alt=&quot;a card my sister got me for my birthday&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that if you’re not a contributor and don’t follow us on Github, it’s hard to see Diaspora grow and evolve. Now that Diaspora is moving into its second year and a new phase of development, here are some numbers on the progress we’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to GitHub, we commit all hours of the day, but we do keep ourselves working our 9-7 most of the time.  We tend to commit mostly after lunch (om nom nom nom nom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/graphs/punch_card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/june01/punchchart.png&quot; title=&quot;punchchart&quot; alt=&quot;punchchart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our developer community is growing.  Diaspora has had over 100 unique code contributors and countless others have edited our wiki and updated Diaspora’s translations in over &lt;a href=&quot;http://99translations.com/public_projects/show/181&quot;&gt;51 languages&lt;/a&gt;.   We have over 4,600 followers and over 840 forks, which means that tons of developers are checking out our code.  That makes us the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/popular/watched&quot;&gt;sixth most popular project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, right behind great open source projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery&quot;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rails/rails&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/node&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/a&gt;, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Number of pageviews of &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;our GitHub page&lt;/a&gt; the last three months&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/graphs/traffic&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/june01/traffic.png&quot; title=&quot;traffic&quot; alt=&quot;traffic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;It’s a group effort! (Click the image to see an interactive impact graph)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/graphs/impact&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/june01/impact.png&quot; title=&quot;impact&quot; alt=&quot;impact&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Want more Diaspora data? Check out our &lt;a href=&quot;/images/diaspora-stats06012011/activity.html&quot;&gt;gitstats!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a developer, you should fork or follow us on GitHub, and hang out in &lt;a href=&quot;http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;#diaspora-dev&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;If you submit one or more &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/wiki/Git-Workflow&quot; title=&quot;s&quot;&gt;well formed pull request&lt;/a&gt;, we will add you as a core commiter to the main repo.&lt;/strong&gt; If you haven’t looked at the code in awhile, now is the best time to jump back in. More developer documentation is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to keep everyone posted about the progress we are making over the next month. We have some really exciting things we can’t wait to announce.  Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay up to Date with Diaspora&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pivotaltracker.com/projects/61641&quot;&gt;Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ci.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;Test Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;Development Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://identi.ca/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;identi.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/c94G4h&quot;&gt;sign up for a beta invite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Moving Forward</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/05/16/moving-forward.html"/>
   <updated>2011-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/05/16/moving-forward</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;16 May 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe, but we’ve been working on Diaspora for a whole year now. And I am happy to report that we’re still here, and we’re going strong. From those first pizza-fueled nights in the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; room at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NYU&lt;/span&gt;, to the Kickstarter going bonkers, to our journey west to San Francisco to work at Pivotal Labs, this past year has been a crazy, unending dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of people besides us are excited about Diaspora. ReadWriteWeb put us on their list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/top_10_startups_of_2010p2.php&quot;&gt;Top Ten Startups of 2011&lt;/a&gt;, Black Duck Software called us the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackducksoftware.com/news/releases/2011-01-07&quot;&gt;Open Source Rookie of the Year,&lt;/a&gt; and our vocal alpha users are giving us great feedback. (Don’t worry, we see your suggestions! There is much to do!)  Heck, if you Google ‘github’, our repository is the third result!*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, we’ve been pretty quiet, because we’ve been hard at work. Ilya and Daniel have been working on some back end changes, focusing on the “share model” (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/m9Udjf&quot;&gt;more detail here&lt;/a&gt;) and building out a framework so pods and client applications can authenticate with each other. These changes are also going to make it easier to interoperate with other federated social networking applications.  Raphael has been working on performance and code cleanup, and I have been trying to brainstorm ways to expand our team, to ensure Diaspora is a long term endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now we have been four dudes and a handful of dedicated open-source contributors trying to listen to user feedback, code new features, help people install software, and talk to the press &amp;#8212; all at once. More than anything, our user feedback has been “go faster.” So go faster is what we are going to do.  If we are going to make Diaspora successful, we need the support from lots of different people.  Recently we have been focused on reaching out to different groups and organizations, and seeing what we can do to get more people involved and invested in Diaspora.  While it takes time away from coding, talking about Diaspora helps hone our vision, and gets even more people excited about what we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next order of business is to state clearly “what we are all about.”  We certainly have not been good at updating people on our work, so unless you have been following us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, you are probably wondering where we are going. Diaspora is a long-term endeavor, and is about an idea bigger than a single feature set or trend. We are working on an outline of what we have learnt so far, and where we see Diaspora going in the next year. We look forward to sharing it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to you soon,&lt;br /&gt;
Maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*5/16/11 Update: Looks like Google updated their index. Now we are not quite third :P&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello From 2011</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/01/31/hello-from-the-new-year.html"/>
   <updated>2011-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2011/01/31/hello-from-the-new-year</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Hello From 2011&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;31 January 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still alive.  It has been eight months since we began work, and we are extremely happy with our progress.  Since we entered our private alpha in November:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:6em;&quot;&gt;Diaspora became the fifth most watched project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/popular/watched&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
         ReadWriteWeb named Diaspora a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/top_10_startups_of_2010p2.php&quot;&gt;Top Ten Startup of 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
         Mashable called us one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2011/01/03/websites-to-watch-in-2011/&quot;&gt;Top 10 Sites to Watch in 2011&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
         Black Duck Software named us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackducksoftware.com/news/releases/2011-01-07&quot;&gt;Open Source Rookie of the Year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year was an amazing year, one we will never forget.  There is much work left to do, but we think 2011 will be the year that Diaspora changes the internet for the better.  We can&amp;#8217;t wait to see what unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are waiting for an alpha invite, please bear with us.  We are grateful we have our Kickstarter backers and their friends testing it out, and we are using their feedback to improve Diaspora constantly.  If you are a Kickstarter backer and you haven’t received an invite, please email feedback@joindiaspora.com, and we’ll take care of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, back to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel, Ilya, Raphael, and Maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you love Ruby or Javascript, Diaspora wants you!  Send us a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/wiki/Git-Workflow&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; and join our community.  No contribution is too small!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Invite Update</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/11/26/joindiaspora-invite-update.html"/>
   <updated>2010-11-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/11/26/joindiaspora-invite-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Invite Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;26 November 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to let you all know, we are closing invited sign-ups for a bit so we can take the great usage data we have received over the last few days and turn them into tangible results. Invites sent to your friends are still valid, but they will need to wait until sometime next week until they are able to accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect an update once we are are ready to send out more invites!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell, Daniel, Raphael, and Ilya&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Private Alpha Invites Going Out Today</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/11/23/private-alpha-released.html"/>
   <updated>2010-11-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/11/23/private-alpha-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Private Alpha Invites Going Out Today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;23 November 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we’re releasing the first set of invites for the Diaspora alpha at &lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;joindiaspora.com&lt;/a&gt;. Every week, we’ll invite more people, starting with our Kickstarter backers, and then moving through our mailing list. By taking these baby steps, we’ll be able to quickly identify performance problems and iterate on features as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are proud of where Diaspora is right now. In less than five months, we’ve gone from nothing to a great starting point from which the community can keep working.  We’ve spent a lot of time thinking about how people can share in a private way, and still do all the things people love to do on social networks. We hope you’ll find it fun to use and a great way to keep in touch with all the people in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora lets you create “aspects,” which are personal lists that let you group people according to the roles they play in your life. We think that aspects are a simple, straightforward, lightweight way to make it really clear who is receiving your posts and who you are receiving posts from. It isn’t perfect, but the best way to improve is to get it into your hands and listen closely to your response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know some things could be better. To name a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continuing to focus on security.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	When we released our initial code, we got some great feedback on better ways to do Rails security. Luckily, it was easy for us to take this feedback and quickly secure the application. We look forward to more such feedback with this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;More extensibility and third-party client APIs.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Third-party clients are a vital part of the social media landscape. We have initial support for connections with some services, but there’s more to do. It’s important for users to be able to use a wide variety of clients and platforms to share on Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Better documentation.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Our community has made great strides in creating documentation to make it easy for anyone to get started with Diaspora. As in most open-source projects, though, there is a lot more to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Easier upgrade path.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Diaspora has been in constant flux since we did our first code release, and we salute those who have been trying to keep their servers up-to-date. We hope to make this easier going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cleaner code.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Our number one goal has been releasing something that works. Sometimes that means making a bit of a mess. Now that we have working features, we can double down on making the code more concise and straightforward, and improving our test suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet signed up to get an invite, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;joindiaspora.com&lt;/a&gt; and do so!  If you remember giving us your email sometime in the past, you can be sure that you will receive an invite soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work is nowhere close to done. To us, that is the best part. There are always more things to improve, more tricks to learn, and more awesome features to add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you on Diaspora,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell, Raphael, Daniel and Ilya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you are a Ruby or JavaScript hacker, Diaspora wants you. We are building a passionate community of developers to keep making Diaspora more awesome. If you enjoy building and breaking the next generation of social tools, we’d love your contributions. &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you’d like to set up a Diaspora server (“pod”) of your own, you can see instructions at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/wiki/&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October Update</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/10/29/october-update.html"/>
   <updated>2010-10-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/10/29/october-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;October Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;29 October 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora is getting better &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/network&quot;&gt;every day&lt;/a&gt;.  Here are some of the features we’ve added over the last month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Public messages are can now be posted to Twitter and Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Friends can now be in multiple aspects&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Re-sharing of status messages to aspects other than the one originally posted to&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An invite system for inviting your friends not hip to Diaspora yet&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Email notifications on new friend request and acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Account data is exportable&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A more friendly “getting started” experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our basic feature set is almost done.  Once that is stable, we’ll set up an alpha server so that anyone, not just developers, can try Diaspora and help us improve it. We’re shooting to do this before Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers, if you haven’t already, please join the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;google group&lt;/a&gt; as I will be posting a more technical update in the next couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilya + Maxwell, Daniel, Raphael&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date with the progress of Diaspora:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;Bug Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ci.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;Test Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/wiki/Roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap &amp;amp; Wishlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;Development Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Highlights of the First Week</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/09/27/highlights-of-the-first-week.html"/>
   <updated>2010-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/09/27/highlights-of-the-first-week</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Highlights of the First Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;27 September 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community’s response to our release has been amazing.  Within the first week of releasing code to developers, Diaspora is the 10th most popular project on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; with over  2500+ watchers.  We’ve had 412 forks of Diaspora to date, and about a half a million views of the code as well.  Many people have gotten the alpha running on their own machines, and have provided countless bug reports and feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks goes out to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/arielo&quot;&gt;arielo&lt;/a&gt; who setup il8n and many others who contributed to translation of diaspora to 17 different languages.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/voxdolo&quot;&gt;voxdolo&lt;/a&gt; has started to help us improve and refactor our specs.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/hemanth&quot;&gt;hemanth&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/maco&quot;&gt;maco&lt;/a&gt; , and &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/drt24&quot;&gt;drt24&lt;/a&gt; who wrote the epic Ubuntu setup script.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/manervu&quot;&gt;manervu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/aredridel&quot;&gt;aredridel&lt;/a&gt; who helped us move to Ruby 1.9.2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to help contribute to Diaspora, you can find the source code on github, accompanied with some instructions on how to get started: &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d also like to thank the people who have reported security holes. Most of what was reported was has already been patched, and if you see any further problems, please let us know at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:exploits@joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;exploits@joindiaspora.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also gotten lots of great feedback about our contributor agreement, and are talking to many experts on the subject to make the agreement more accurately reflect our goals for Diaspora.  We’ve outlined what we want that document to express &lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com/licensing.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week of Diaspora source code being released has been huge.  Project releases like this just don’t happen everyday, and we are completely overwhelmed that so many people want to help make Diaspora awesome.  We are doing our best to get as many people involved as soon as possible.  Thank you so much for your continued support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS. Today is Rafi&amp;#8217;s birthday.  (He&amp;#8217;ll be in &lt;a href=&quot;irc://irc.freenode.net/#diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;#diaspora-dev&lt;/a&gt; all day.)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Developer Release</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/09/15/developer-release.html"/>
   <updated>2010-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/09/15/developer-release</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Developer Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;15 September 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we are releasing the source code for Diaspora.  This is now a community project and development is open to anyone with the technical expertise who shares the vision of a social network that puts users in control.  From now on, we will be working closely with the community on improving and solidifying Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began the summer with a list of technologies, a few bold claims, and the goal of making an intrinsically more private social network.  The overwhelming response that we elicited made us realize that technology woudn’t be enough.  Even the most powerful, granular set of dropdowns and checkboxes will never give people control over where their content is going, let alone give them ownership of their digital self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live our real lives in context, speaking from whatever aspect of ourselves that those around us know.  Social tools should work the same way.  Getting the source into the hands of developers is our first experiment in making a simple and functional tool for contextual sharing.  Diaspora is in its infancy, but our initial ideas are there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora now:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/stream.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Share status messages and photos privately and in near real time with your friends through “aspects”.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Friend people across the Internet no matter where Diaspora seed is located.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/manage_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/manage_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/manage_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Manage friends using “aspects”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/photo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/drag_and_drop_photos.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/album.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/albums.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Upload of photos and albums&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;All traffic is signed and encrypted (except photos, for now).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things we are working on next for our Alpha in October:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Facebook Integration&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Internationalization&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Data Portability&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are our current priorities, for more detail check out our roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of our focus this summer was centered around publishing content to groups of your friends, wherever their seed may live.  It is by no means bug free or feature complete, but it is an important step for putting us, the users, in control. Developers, our code is on github, our tracker is public, we have a developer mailing list, and we are happily accepting patches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/diaspora/diaspora&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pivotaltracker.com/projects/61641&quot;&gt;Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ci.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;Test Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diaspora/diaspora/wiki/Roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap &amp;amp; Wishlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-dev&quot;&gt;Development Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/diaspora-discuss&quot;&gt;Discuss Mailing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date with the progress of Diaspora:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://identi.ca/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;identi.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/c94G4h&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS:&lt;br /&gt;
Feel free to try to get it running on your machines and use it, but we give no guarantees.  We know there are security holes and bugs, and your data is not yet fully exportable.  If you do find something, be sure to log it in our bugtracker, and we would love screenshots and browser info.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An Overdue Update</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/08/26/overdue-update.html"/>
   <updated>2010-08-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/08/26/overdue-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;An Overdue Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;26 August 2010 (Edited 30 August 2010)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Internet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since August is nearly over, it is time for an update and answers to some questions.  We have been coding.  We have Diaspora working, we like it, and it will be open-sourced on September 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are spending a good chunk of time concentrating on building clear, contextual sharing.  That means an intuitive way for users to decide, and not notice deciding, what content goes to their coworkers and what goes to their drinking buddies.  We know that&amp;#8217;s a hard UI problem and we take it seriously.   The publicity and money that you have given us has let us work with great designers like Janice Frasier, through her new program &lt;a href=&quot;http://luxr.posterous.com/&quot;&gt;LUXr&lt;/a&gt;, whose constant reminders that we are not the user have kept us honest and focused.  Pivotal Labs has also helped us prioritize, and we have pushed back more technical features like plugins and APIs in favor of simple and high value features.  Our original goals remain the same, and these features are still in our timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been an epic summer.  We want to say thank you to the people involved with the Federated Social Web Summit in Portland.  There, we ate bagels with Evan Prodromou and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.net&quot;&gt;Status.net&lt;/a&gt; crew, and got to meet the people behind some of the great tools that make up the foundation of Diaspora.  We are honored to be a part of building this new kind of web.  We&amp;#8217;ve also visited and given talks at a few places in the Bay Area like Mozilla and Razorfish.  &lt;b&gt;Edit (8/30): Here&amp;#8217;s a video of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://videos.mozilla.org/serv/marketing/brownbags/2010-08-20-diaspora.ogg&quot;&gt;Mozilla talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aren’t going to stop working after we release.  Ilya and Raphael are taking leave from &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NYU&lt;/span&gt;, and we will continue to develop and maintain Diaspora as a long term project.  We have shifted our development timeline accordingly,  and the first release will be the beginning of something great, not a finished summer project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next couple weeks, Dan, Ilya, and Raphael are going to be getting some well deserved R&amp;amp;R at Burning Man, and Max will be speaking at Ars Electronica in Linz, Austria.  Thats all for now, but we will will post another update about September 15th soon.  There still is much more work to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Addendum (8/30): To clarify, September 15 will be our open-source developer release.  At that time, we will open up our &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; repository, publish our roadmap, and shift our development style to be more community oriented.  We intend on launching a consumer facing alpha in October.  Join our &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/Vebk&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; to get an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited all four of us are staying on the project full-time!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your keyboards polished for the 15th,&lt;br /&gt;
- Ilya, Raphael, Maxwell and Daniel&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>One Month In</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/07/01/one-month-in.html"/>
   <updated>2010-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/07/01/one-month-in</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;One Month In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 July 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings from San Francisco!  Today is July 1st, so that means today we are going to be sharing what we have been working on the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting settled in ole San Fran, our first day at Pivotal Labs was June 7th.  Not only has Pivotal lent us desks and monitors for the summer, they push us daily to drive development from the interface and focus on the experience, rather than providing &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; a tool for developers to hack on.  Getting periodic help from Pivots has already been transformative on the outcome of Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Pivotal Labs, thanks for letting us use your stuff, eat your food, and for teaching us your agile ninja ways. We owe you one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What have we been working on?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During June, we have been focusing on developing a system for passing different forms of information in between seeds.  When you post a status message on your seed, it gets pushed over &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; in real time to all of your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also started to build the latest and greatest in web standards into Diaspora.  Websockets are already in the Diaspora core, and any Diaspora plugins will be able to have rapid two-way functionality, (think chat, games etc) almost effortlessly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the screen shots!  Most of the cool things for this month you can see in our video, here.  (I know you all were itching for another really awkward video from us, so consider your wish granted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is real&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Real time message passing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone on your friends list is pushed a copy of your messages.  Additionally, if any of your friends comment on your post, the comment is sent back to the post’s owner, and back down to all of your other friends.  These seed are on the internet (in different places, too) and are speedy and lightweight.  This allows us to create a real time feed of all of your friends’ updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Websocket &amp;#8211; Ajaxy goodness.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to real time message passing, you are notified all of your friends’ messages which are push to your server as soon as it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is faked for the purposes of this demonstration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;User pictures&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a hard problem, we just haven’t addressed it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DEMO&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a video of Dan and I showing sending a couple of status messages in between two Diaspora seeds.  You can see the comments trickling down to both friends&amp;#8217; feeds.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/13026281&quot;&gt;video here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we have a video with us using a bunch of different diaspora seeds.  They are all on different servers, and all friended with the same person.  When we have that person send out 10 messages in rapid succession, you can see how fast their friends are updated.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=13026173&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=13026173&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/13026173&quot;&gt;Diaspora Message Propagation (pre-alpha!)&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user3612554&quot;&gt;daniel grippi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we have a few screenshots.  We wanted to do a little story novella, but actually since posting any update pushes it out to friends so fast, we forgot to get a screencap of their friends page without their messages. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/adams.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/jefferson.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/washington.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whats next for us?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Coding and more coding.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had a great run our first month, and we show no signs of stopping.  We are weeks ahead of schedule in terms of robustness, thanks to Pivotal Labs. We have been rather quiet (which really brings out the doubters), but I promise that is because we are working hard to make Diaspora awesome.  Bear with us for the next few months, it will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have been asking us almost every day what our development schedule is, and when we plan to finish exactly, and the honest truth is we don’t have an exact day.  With one week “sprints,” lots of end-to-end, user driven features are being added every day.  We try and “theme” our months to be features around a given area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The month’s themes (subject to change):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;June&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Real Time Message passing between seeds&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Building the core of the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;July&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;OStatus/Standards compliance&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Encryption Layer&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Implement awesome user interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;August&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Plugins&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Services(including FB) integration&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; Refator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;September&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Prep for source code freedom!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like we came in right on schedule for June :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another exciting development is that we have been invited to attend the Federated Social Web Summit in Portland Oregon on July 18th.  There we will meet with all of the awesome people working in this space, exchange cool ideas, and make some lasting relationships.  Special thanks to the people behind Status.net who have been hard at work organizing the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all we have for you right now, now it’s time for us to tackle July!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maxwell&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Little More Than 24 Hours Left!</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/31/a-little-more-than-24-hours-left.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/31/a-little-more-than-24-hours-left</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A Little More Than 24 Hours Left!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;31 May 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we started our Kickstarter, we thought our $10,000 would come from our immediate friends, family, and a small handful generous strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, were we wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up with close to twenty times our goal from over 6200 individuals who share our vision. By our second week in, we gained the attention of some extraordinary developers, the New York Times, the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/span&gt;, and Gizmodo, among others. The sheer number of current supporters is unprecedented on Kickstarter, and we are thankful for every last backer. Together, we have struck a chord with the world and identified a problem which needs to be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with the goal of working hard, staying focused, and making great software, and that&amp;#8217;s exactly what we&amp;#8217;re going to do. With the surplus of attention and monetary support, we are now able to position ourselves amongst some of the best developers around. You may not hear too much from us in the coming months and we will try our best to provide regular updates, but our silence means we are hard at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before our Kickstarter is over, we just wanted to address a few questions about rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the fund raising period is over, we (via Kickstarter) will send out a form to collect the address where you want your rewards sent. All rewards are going to be fulfilled at the end of the summer, around the time Diaspora is going to be released. With that being said, when we started our Kickstarter, we thought the logisitcs of delivering two hundred or so CDs, stickers and shirts would be simple. We thought it would be a nice token of gratitude for our backers, even though in this day and age, shipping frequently updated open source software doesn&amp;#8217;t actually make much sense. For each of our backers, we plan on providing exclusive, high bandwidth links and torrents of the latest version of Diaspora on launch day. This will always be the best way to get Diaspora, as you can guarantee that it will be the most up to date version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we send out the request for contact information, we hope you will choose an instantaneous download, rather than a silly outdated CD. If for any reason you feel like you want the CD, please just say, &amp;#8220;I want the CD!&amp;#8221; and we will be more than happy to send it to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for the stickers and the tee-shirt. If for any reason, you feel like you do not want them, let us use the money we save to make Diaspora even more awesome. If you want it, don&amp;#8217;t feel bad! Just make sure you wear your Diaspora shirt with pride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you donated at any reward pledge level, you are entitled to your reward, and we are looking forward to getting you your awesome Diaspora stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have set up an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joindiaspora.com/faq.html&quot;&gt;FAQs&lt;/a&gt; on our website which we are constantly updating as well, and you can send any other further questions to &lt;strong&gt;questions AT joindiaspora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DOT&lt;/span&gt; com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again, &lt;br /&gt;
- Maxwell, Ilya, Raphael, and Daniel&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>After the Times</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/17/after-the-times.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/17/after-the-times</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;After the Times&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;17 May 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We realize we&amp;#8217;ve been conspicuously absent the past few days.  As you can imagine, we&amp;#8217;ve been overwhelmed by the degree of the enthusiasm about Diaspora, and we wanted to wait a few days to to let the craziness settle down.  Over 4600 people care enough about Diaspora&amp;#8217;s goals and have enough confidence in us to sign up for Kickstarter and back us.  Now that we have much more money than we asked for, our situation has changed a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our basic plan is the same: we&amp;#8217;re going to build a great lightweight decentralized social networking framework and release it as &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AGPL&lt;/span&gt; software.  We&amp;#8217;re going to use the extra money to help us reach that goal and to keep improving Diaspora after this summer, and possibly supplement our ramen with the occasional apple. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to money, a massive number of talented and experienced people, including developers, designers, hosting companies and lawyers, have offered us their expertise.  Though we haven&amp;#8217;t responded to the deluge of emails, we have read them all.  We&amp;#8217;re still working through the backlog and are putting together a great group of advisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re also getting in touch with other projects in the space.  We had a great talk with the guys behind Ostatus earlier this week, and we are excited to implement the OStatus standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, we couldn&amp;#8217;t have made it this far without all of our incredible supporters.  It heartens us to know that so many people share our concern for privacy online and we are doing our best to make sure Diaspora turns out awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell, Daniel, Raphael and Ilya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Diaspora Team&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We Made It!</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/08/we-did-it.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/05/08/we-did-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;We Made It!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;08 May 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thank-you-diaspora.full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;#8217;t believe it only took us twelve days to reach our goal. We have gotten so much support and exposure thanks to all of you that we could barely keep up with all of your emails, updates, and comments. We really appreciate people who continue to back us, it makes us so pumped to get started on the project. We think people&amp;#8217;s privacy and personal control is in jeopardy more than ever online, and every day we hear about more and more of our peers who say that Diaspora is something that they want and need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your comments, updates, and emails are all still very appreciated. We also want to extend a special thank you to all of our many international backers (we promise we are going to find you a way to get you your rewards&amp;#8230;we had no idea we would get such worldwide support)! We are really excited that our summer is going to become a reality, and can&amp;#8217;t wait to make Diaspora the social application we all need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, for the Diaspora team, we have to finish school/graduate. Then, we are going to spend a week or two getting ready for three months of intense coding. We will try and update our blog (and even our Kickstarter) periodically over the summer, but for the most part we are going to be in recluse programmer mode. If you want to see what we are up to, we will be hanging out on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt; Social mailing list, as well as a few other places as we work on defining some common protocols between like minded projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you can check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for updates, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://identi.ca/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;Identica&lt;/a&gt;, and soon, on Diaspora itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell, Daniel, Raphael and Ilya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Diaspora Team&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We Made It Half Way!</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/30/we-made-it-half-way.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/30/we-made-it-half-way</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;We Made It Half Way!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;30 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow! After just one week, we are now half-way to our goal!  It has been a really crazy ride for us, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/starkness/status/13046623398&quot;&gt;the support&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hult/status/13077480233&quot;&gt;excitement&lt;/a&gt; we have been getting is absolutely &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/brokep/status/13078993912&quot;&gt;unreal&lt;/a&gt;.  However, there is still half way to go!  We (the team) are still thinking of new ways we can reach people, and we certainly won&amp;#8217;t stop working hard to make sure we achieve our goal.  So many of you have reached out to us to lend a hand, and if you have been helping us out, or even just reposting our stuff, thank you so much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a couple of cool things to announce next week, so be sure to keep a look out another post sometime soon for more info about that.  It has been great following many of you on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joindiaspora&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see that so many people are excited about these problems as we are.  Every time we see a new relevant update from you all reminds us why we want to make Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all for being so awesome, we can&amp;#8217;t wait till our finals are over so we can get crackin&amp;#8217; on Diaspora!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Also, for a slightly more technical update, &lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com/2010/04/30/a-response-to-mr-villa.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is our response to Mozilla&amp;#8217;s Luis Villa.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://kck.st/9QC2zk'&gt;&lt;img border='0' src='http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/196017994/diaspora-the-personally-controlled-do-it-all-distr/widget/card.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Questions From Luis Villa</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/30/a-response-to-mr-villa.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/30/a-response-to-mr-villa</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Questions From Luis Villa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;30 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday, Luis Villa &lt;a href=&quot;http://tieguy.org/blog/2010/04/27/questions-for-the-diaspora/&quot;&gt;blogged about us&lt;/a&gt; and asked us some questions.  We really appreciated him taking the time to offer us his constructive feedback, so thanks Luis.  It is nice to know we have some awesome people looking out for us.  We&amp;#8217;ve taken a couple days to try to answer well, and of course, we&amp;#8217;ll think about any suggestions and elaborate on whatever questions are left open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you think are the most important features a social network should have? How would you prioritize them? Do you plan to Build Less  or go big? If building less, what is the minimal set of features you can get away with?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to &amp;#8220;build less.&amp;#8221;  These are the features which we aim to complete first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A good secure protocol, encrypted at every leg, including a specification for a lightweight, probably &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt;, RESTful set of routes.  We see all of this communication happening between two Diaspora servers, rather than strictly between peers.  We realize there is the problem with polling with this model, but we think there are several tricks worth trying which all have their relative pros and cons: PubSub (fast and easy, requires some level of centralization), querying friends servers from the browser side and posting responses back (requires browser side decryption) to name a couple.  Alternatively, we are considering going with &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XMPP&lt;/span&gt; altogether due to the ability to be able to push content between nodes, but we need to research it further to see if it is something we would want to implement.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A datastore and corresponding interface that can store all of your stuff in one place. MongoDB is what we are looking at for V1, but  the redundancy of TahoeFS is intriguing(as well as serving a slightly different purpose).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A clear extension framework.   Diaspora will be service-agnostic and we will need to make it easy to import from and export to any format/web service.  It is also our goal to make Diaspora as content-agnostic as possible, by providing abstract data types and an easily extended UI so that whatever new content people want to store and share can be integrated without re-rewriting parts of the whole application stack.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Be your own OpenID provider.  Having a single identity across lots of services is great, but why trust a web service to hold it?  Once we are the keepers of our own data, we can also selectively allow services access to it through Oauth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will come out of this summer is this basic framework, well tested and documented.  We will write backend interfaces for some services, but I think the community will be able outperform us in bandwidth and quality on this one.  It is fundamental to the success of the project that the code be 100% free, or the project will fail.  End of story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DiSo is now two-plus years old. Any ideas why it didn’t get off the ground? Bonus points: same question for Mugshot.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that “Getting Real”&amp;#8217;s concept of “Failing Fast&amp;quot; applies here.  It seems to us that all of the previous attempts at solving the problem are trying to create the perfect solution in the first version.  We realize that hard problems do not have immediate good answers.  One of the best things I learned in school was taught to me by the fantastic professor and puzzle master &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.nyu.edu/cs/faculty/shasha/&quot;&gt;Dennis Shasha&lt;/a&gt;.  To paraphrase his “heuristic for solving hard problems”, “when dealing with a difficult problem, build something that satisfies the problem first, then worry about making your solution elegant, bullet proof, and faster later.”  We have seen a lot of projects trying to be everything to everyone.  They become godzilla specs, with features to satisfy everyone involved.   So much time is spent in planning and arguing about implementation details, that A) nothing ever actually get coded and experimented with B) if any new problem is somehow discovered in said gargantuan plan, it goes back to the drawing board, and the fundamental problem does not get solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem itself is not what server architecture, or what language we code in, or even what standards what we support.  While these questions are very important in making any solution better and more robust, they are all implementation details. The core problem is that users who want to share with their friends have &lt;b&gt;no&lt;/b&gt; better alternative.  We think any solution which addresses this problem is a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;a href=&quot;http://identi.ca/notice/30119960&quot;&gt;said yourself&lt;/a&gt; that you have seen vaporware projects in this space in the past, and we have too. We think a project focused getting something out there should be priority #1.  We need to try a bunch of approaches, and see which ones take off, and we need to do it quickly.  We are not going to support every service under the sun from day one, and we are going to have to accept certain problems and limitations.  Ultimately, all we want is to release something coherent, something we can get constructive feedback so we can iterate again, and deal with problems as they arise, rather than trying to plan around all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer directly,  I am pretty sure &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DISO&lt;/span&gt; failed because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;They tried to add on to Wordpress, a project which was not designed from the ground up to be a distributed network.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(a guess) they quickly tried to support all sort of features without building some sort of common infrastructure before trying to add functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they did spawn “activity streams,” which seems like a promising protocol we are interested in supporting. I had no awareness of Mugshot before you pointed it out, so I won&amp;#8217;t yank around your chain and make something up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What standards, if any, do you plan to work with/build on? (just to throw out a couple, all of which have strengths and flaws to consider: webfinger, oauth, xauth, the buzz APIs.)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What other services, if any, do you want to interoperate with? why? how will you prioritize?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I mentioned Oauth, OpenID, and ActivityStreams.  We want to support content types out of the box, rather than individual services.  We have a friend working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salmon-protocol.org/&quot;&gt;Salmon Protocol&lt;/a&gt; , and we think Diaspora could work really well with that, and things like PubStub also may be useful.  We are also talking with people involved with the “good part” of the Open Graph Protocol, as well as the fledgling OpenLike.  Webfinger seems like it would be simple enough to integrate and perhaps structure our profile model around.  Also, we are getting lots of helpful feedback about OStatus.  Once our extension framework is fairly final, we will be building interfaces to services and standards, and we will help out anyone who wants to build an interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Any other Libre code bases in the same space you’d like to work with? &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt; Social? StatusNet? What ones are you aware of, and why will you/won’t you build on/work with those?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been keeping track of &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.fsf.org/wiki/Group:GNU_Social&quot;&gt;daisycha.in/GNUSocial&lt;/a&gt; and hope to solve some of our common problems on their lists.  We know &lt;a href=&quot;http://status.net&quot;&gt;status.net&lt;/a&gt; from our time at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FCNYU&lt;/span&gt; also have looked at some other things, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://themineproject.org/about/&quot;&gt;The Mine Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onesocialweb.org/&quot;&gt;onesocialweb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://noserub.com/&quot;&gt;Noserub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
and we are huge fans of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lorea.cc&quot;&gt;lorea.cc&lt;/a&gt; website&amp;#8230;  :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be constantly sharing our ideas, and 100% of our code at the end of the summer.  Some of our common problems may spawn new libraries which will be also be free. The protocol discussion is important to have with the community, and we would like to see it be as lightweight and flexible as possible.  We want to be an independent code base because the four of us work fast and well as a team.  Our arguments are short and solved by someone writing better code.  Plus, maybe we are just too in love with our tools, but we love Git and Ruby. We can try things quickly, there are great web libraries, and more and more hosts are providing support for Rails apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Would a smarter client (like Mozilla Contacts) be useful to you? If so, how?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had not considered something like Mozilla Contacts until I saw it earlier this week.  Our initial thoughts were that we would not want to tie one&amp;#8217;s accessibility to a browser.  We wanted a user&amp;#8217;s Diaspora seed to take care of all of the hard work server-side, because you should be able to access all of your information from any computer or device connected to the web, and we want to try and provide an experience to the user as close to what they are used to as possible.  We  have thrown around the idea of having the option of doing decryption browser side via some sort of browser add-on, and we perhaps it could also be used with some sort of “smarter client”.  This would come in later versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is the strategy to get to a critical mass of users (or avoid having to get a critical mass?)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think that there is a solid contingent of people who would want to host their own node.  How many people host their own blog?  That’s not certainly Facebook numbers, but once we get that first kernel of people using it, we think people will see that having (at least) a copy of your data which you can apply to anything is a really empowering proposition, and not just in a social networking context.  We think in the future (after the summer), we will work on an easy installation, but for right now, we want to make this software because we want to use it, there is at least a good handful of others who do too.  Certainly the interwebs have been aflutter about this idea for awhile as well, and I think people would be willing to give a crack at something that works that isn&amp;#8217;t Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What are your three favorite books on software development? three favorite essays? what about on design?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this one of the questions where if I don’t say “Kernighan and Ritchie,” “Getting Real”, “Mythical Man-Month,” “Don’t Make Me Think!” or something like that, you will disapprove? :)  We like all of those books plenty.  In all honesty, much of what we read is random blogs we find on the Internet.  Certainly not all of it is of perfect and high quality, but I think since we all love to code, we always consuming some sort of writing about design patterns, development, and cool new testing ideas.  Regular devs have great ideas about code every day, and we like getting a variety of opinions. &lt;br /&gt;
(Worth noting that actually if you wanted to share &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;YOUR&lt;/span&gt; favorite books/essays/blog posts, we would love to check them out.  We certainly haven&amp;#8217;t been around as long as you old dudes, so I am sure there is much you could share with us, and we would be totally stoked to get some suggestions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To actually answer your question: Not to sound like a Ruby slog, but I actually do love “The Ruby Programming Language”  written by its creator Yukihiro Matsumoto.  One of my favorite things about the language is how Matz included so many different idioms on how to do the same thing; that way, you can pick the subset of the Ruby language that feels natural to you.  In the book, I love seeing how “natural” feels to Matz, and how he explains that this is only “his” way to write Ruby, and you should find your own way.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/span&gt; found his.&lt;/a&gt;  Even better,  Ilya and Maxwell got the chance to meet Matz three weeks ago for dinner in Brooklyn.  We bought him some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caracasarepabar.com/index_2.php&quot;&gt;arepas&lt;/a&gt;. They were delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finally, we wanted to touch on your point about being a pragmatist.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think we are pretty pragmatic guys too(maybe not quite &lt;a href=&quot;http://tieguy.org&quot;&gt;tieguys&lt;/a&gt;), but there is something we just don&amp;#8217;t quite understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say you don’t have the time or money to work on such a project, one you yourself identify as important. That makes tons of sense to us.  There are plenty of things we would like to do and we don&amp;#8217;t have the time for, and we are not even married or have jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that is the case however, what would be un-pragmatic about giving four excited dudes who spent their last semester of school thinking about a problem you are &amp;#8220;worried-about-but-can&amp;#8217;t-deal-with-now,&amp;#8221; twenty bucks so they can take an honest crack at solving it? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that this cleared up some of your questions Luis.  Thank you again, and we look forward to your continued constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maxwell, Daniel, Raphael, and Ilya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EDIT&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/maxwell/diaspora_public_site/commit/6748cff913f7237aee5e16877b6a25abeec08258&quot;&gt;9:47am &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EST&lt;/span&gt; 04/30/10&amp;#8230;small typo changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kickstarter Pitch</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/27/kickstarter-pitch.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/27/kickstarter-pitch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Kickstarter Pitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;14 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is taken from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://kck.st/9QC2zk&quot;&gt;kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;.  You should check it out for more info.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;Diaspora&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; the privacy aware, personally controlled, do-it-all distributed &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; social network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are four talented young programmers from &lt;a href=&quot;http://cims.nyu.edu&quot;&gt;NYU’s Courant Institute&lt;/a&gt; trying to raise money so we can spend the summer building Diaspora; an open source personal web server that will put individuals in control of their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter your Diaspora “seed,” a personal web server that stores all of your information and shares it with your friends. Diaspora knows how to securely share (using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_Privacy_Guard&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) your pictures, videos, and more. When you have a Diaspora seed of your own, you own your social graph, you have access to your information however you want, whenever you want, and you have full control of your online identity. Once we have built a solid foundation, we will make Diaspora easy to extend to facilitate any type of communication, and the possibilities will be endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a little more detailed explanation, checkout &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joindiaspora.com/2010/04/21/a-little-more-about-the-project.html&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is the project about?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that privacy and connectedness do not have to be mutually exclusive. With Diaspora, we are reclaiming our data, securing our social connections, and making it easy to share on your own terms. We think we can replace today&amp;#8217;s centralized social web with a more secure and convenient decentralized network. Diaspora will be easy to use, and it will be centered on you instead of a faceless hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why are we building it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This February, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eben_Moglen&quot;&gt;Eben Moglen&lt;/a&gt;, Columbia law professor and author of the latest &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, gave a talk on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QOEMv0S8AcA&quot;&gt;Internet privacy.&lt;/a&gt; As more and more of our lives and identities become digitized, Moglen explains, the convenience of putting all of our information in the hands of companies on “the cloud” is training us to casually sacrifice our privacy and fragment our online identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is centralization so much more convenient, even in an age where relatively powerful computers are ubiquitous? Why is there no good alternative to centralized services that, as Moglen pointed out, comes with &amp;quot;spying for free?” Why do we keep our personal data in a thousand places? We have the technology, someone just needs to take the time to figure out how we can communicate smoothly and intuitively, without the hidden costs of “the cloud”. As good programmers, when we noticed that the application we need doesn&amp;#8217;t exist, we set out to fill the hole in our digital lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why do we need money?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a plan, &lt;a href=&quot;http://joindiaspora.com/project.html&quot;&gt;a bunch of ideas&lt;/a&gt; and the programming chops to build Diaspora. What we need is the time it takes to iron out a powerful, secure, and elegant piece of software. Daniel, Ilya, Raphael, and Maxwell are all ready to trade our internships and summer jobs for three months totally focused on building Diaspora. We want to write code all the time, everyday. Once we have made our first solid iteration, we are going to release our code as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software&quot;&gt;free software&lt;/a&gt; so everyone can make Diaspora even better. $10,000 buys the software for everyone who wants to use it, forever. We think it can change the way people communicate and empower individuals to permanently take control of their online identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we open source our source code, we hope to also provide a paid turnkey hosted service in the vein of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt; to make it easy for people who want to use Diaspora, but don’t want to deal with the fuss of setting it up.* We will make it easy to export your data and configuration, so if you decide you want to graduate and host your seed yourself, you are free to do so at anytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is for everyone to have full control over their data and to empower people in to become responsible, secure, and social Internet dwellers. We believe offering this service will be helpful to non-technical users who are also worried about their data and privacy online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Our Promise.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We promise to you that Diaspora will be &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affero_General_Public_License&quot;&gt;aGPL&lt;/a&gt; software which will released at the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Want more info?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our website for project updates, blog posts, pictures, and plans. More information is being added every day! &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joindiaspora.com&quot;&gt;www.joindiaspora.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out more videos &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/user/mbs348&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want get Diaspora updates via email? &lt;a href=&quot;http://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?key=0AoQmncVLKXRBdFo1N3o4R3lrWkszX0dIQm9vemp5TWc&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Sign up here!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
*this service will be available a few months after the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dan Made Some Awesome Flyers</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/24/awesome-flyers-are-here.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/24/awesome-flyers-are-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Dan Made Some Awesome Flyers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;24 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan just made some radical flyers for Ilya to handout at a meeting tomorrow.  In case you feel like plastering your hometown with them too, here is a nice image of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;80%&quot; src=&quot;/images/diaspora_handouts_printout.png&quot; alt=&quot;diaspora handouts&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kickstarter is up!</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/24/10-kickstarter-is-up.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/24/10-kickstarter-is-up</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Kickstarter is up!&lt;br /&gt;
p(meta). 24 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone!  The Kickstarter is finally up for the project.  We have some serious fundraising to do, but we think that with the help of the Kickstarter and Free Software Communities, we can make it happen.  It would be awesome if you checked our our KS page and clicked that big &amp;#8220;Back this Project&amp;#8221; button.  We think we have some neat rewards to offer, not to mention Diaspora itself will be a great reward for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, keep us in mind won&amp;#8217;t you? Maybe even pass this awesome widget on&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://kck.st/9QC2zk'&gt;&lt;img border='0' src='http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/196017994/diaspora-the-personally-controlled-do-it-all-distr/widget/card.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Little More About The Project</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/21/a-little-more-about-the-project.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/21/a-little-more-about-the-project</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A Little More About The Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;21 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora aims to be a distributed network, where totally separate computers connect to each other directly, will let us connect without surrendering our privacy.  We call these computers &amp;#8216;seeds&amp;#8217;.  A seed is owned by you, hosted by you, or on a rented server.  Once it has been set up, the seed will aggregate all of your information: your facebook profile, tweets, anything.  We are designing an easily extendable plugin framework for Diaspora, so that whenever newfangled content gets invented, it will be automagically integrated into every seed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your information in your seed, it will connect to every service you used to have for you.  For example, your seed will keep pulling tweets and you will still be able to see your Facebook newsfeed.  In fact, Diaspora will make those services better!  Upload an image to Flickr and your seed can automatically generate a tweet from the caption and link.  Social networking will just get better when you have control over your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seed will not just be all your existing networks put together, though.  Decentralizing lets us reconstruct our “social graphs” so that they belong to us. Our real social lives do not have central managers, and our virtual lives do not need them.  Friend another seed and the two of you can synchronize over a direct and secure connection instead of through a superfluous hub.  Encryption (privacy nerds: we’re using &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPG&lt;/span&gt;) will ensure that no matter what kind of content is being transferred, you can share privately. Eventually, today&amp;#8217;s hubs could be almost entirely replaced by a decentralized network of truly personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more updates on updates, and be sure to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://kck.st/9QC2zk&quot;&gt;Kickstarter!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>reason number x</title>
   <link href="http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/17/links-for-the-day.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.blog.joindiaspora.com//2010/04/17/links-for-the-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;reason number x&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;17 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every few days, we will post a few interesting links we feel somehow relates confirms why we all need diasproa now more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
